Guide to the Joseph Ingram Sr. papers, 1769-1935 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Joseph Ingram Sr. papers 1769-1935 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Ingram, Joseph, Sr.
2.5 Linear Feet Approx. 1,130 Items
Joseph Ingram Sr. was a member of the Ingram family of Anson County, North Carolina.
The collection contains family and business papers and correspondence of Joseph Ingram, Dr. E. N. Ingram, and various members of the Ingram family. The bulk of the collection belongs to the first half of the nineteenth century, and includes materials pertaining to the cotton industry, slavery, transportation, and social and economic conditions in Anson County, North Carolina.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Joseph Ingram Sr. papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1948.
Collection Overview
The collection contains family and business papers and correspondence of Joseph Ingram, Dr. E. N. Ingram, and various members of the Ingram family. The bulk of the collection belongs to the first half of the nineteenth century, and includes materials referring to the cotton industry, slavery, transportation, and social and economic conditions in Anson County, North Carolina.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Ingram, Joseph, Sr.
Ingram, E.N.
Ingram family
Business records -- North Carolina -- Anson County
Cotton trade -- North Carolina
Slavery -- North Carolina
Transportation -- Southern States
Anson County (N.C.) -- History
North Carolina -- Economic conditions
North Carolina -- Social conditions
Contents of Collection
- Joseph Ingram Sr. papers, 1769-1935 and undated, (5 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1769-1879 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2)
  - Legal documents, 1781-1877 (Box 2)
  - Medical notes (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1774-1839 (Box 3)
  - Bills and receipts, 1840-1879 and undated (Box 4)
  - Printed material (Box 4)
  - Printed material (Box 5)
  - Various volumes (Box 5)
  - The Descendants of Winfred Nelms and Joseph Ingram (Box 5)